Finding Aid for the Sara Holroyd World War II and George Peabody College for Teachers Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Sara Holroyd World War II and George Peabody College for Teachers Collection
2007
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0654
.42 linear feet
Biographical Note
Sara Holroyd, from Selma, Alabama, came to Peabody to study music. While a student at George Peabody College for Teachers she was awarded many honors and was elected President of the Student Body and “Miss Peabody” in her senior year. She was a member of the college choir, orchestra, and band, and sang with the Peabody Madrigalians. She graduated in 1946. In 1951 she received a M.A. from Columbia, and afterwards she had a career in education as a Professor of Music at the University of Kentucky at Lexington.
Sara Holroyd still lives in Lexington, Kentucky, and her interview for the Vandy Goes to War World War II Remembered Oral History Project is included in that important archive of Vanderbilt’s history.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection (.42 linear feet ) contains letters, programs, and newspaper clippings collected by Sara Holroyd, a 1946 graduate of George Peabody College for Teachers. (Peabody merged Vanderbilt University in 1979.). Ms. Holroyd was a student leader and a musician while at Peabody, and many of the programs feature her as a student musician. This collection also chronicles the end of WWII and activities at Peabody College during that time.
- File Listing
  - Correspondence
    - Outgoing—Sara Holroyd to her mother on the end of WWII, Aug. 15, 1945; on election to “Miss Peabody”, May 23, 1946 (Folder 1)
    - Incoming—Evelyn Stephenson with accompanying news article “The Four Melodears”, Jan. 16, 1984 (Folder 2)
  - Personal and Biographical
    - As Officer and President of the Peabody Student Body—newspaper clippings (Folder 3)
    - Sara Holroyd, musician, including the script for the Gay Nineties Revue and newspaper clippings (Folder 4)
    - Sara Holroyd “Miss Peabody” June 1946—newspaper clippings (Folder 5)
    - Sara Holroyd “Miss Peabody” June 1946—newspaper clippings (Folder 6)
    - Honors and awards (Folder 7)
    - Peabody graduation awards and honors for Sara Holroyd—newspaper clippings (Folder 8)
    - Graduation from Peabody, including official invitation (Folder 9)
    - Graduation from Peabody—Prom cards and other items (Folder 10)
    - Graduation from Peabody—letters and telegrams (Folder 11)
    - Peabody Band—newspaper clippings (Folder 12)
    - Peabody College friends, teachers, and events—newspaper clippings (Folder 13)
    - Peabody College—newspaper clippings (Folder 14)
    - Certificate—Mary Mildred Sullivan Scholarship, March 19, 1945 (Folder 15)
    - Certificate—Sigma Alpha Iota, May 10, 1947 (Folder 16)
  - Programs
    - George Peabody College--Graduation, June 7, 1946; august 23, 1946; June 6, 1947 (Folder 17)
    - George Peabody College—featuring Sara Holroyd, Dec. 12, 1943—Aug. 19, 1946 (Folder 18)
    - George Peabody College—Christmas/Messiah, Dec. 11, 1943—Dec. 11, 1945 (Folder 19)
    - George Peabody College—Graduate, Faculty, and other recitals, Dec. 6, 1943—August 6, 1946 (Folder 20)
    - George Peabody College—Student Recitals, Dec.9, 1943—July 31, 1946 (Folder 21)
    - George Peabody College—Music and Dance, June 6, 1944—June 5, 1947 (Folder 22)
    - George Peabody College—Peabody Choir and Madrigalians, April 23, 1945 (Folder 23)
    - George Peabody College—Chamber Music, March 31, 1944—July 29, 1946 (Folder 24)
    - George Peabody College—College Band, Nov. 21, 1944—July 2, 1946 (Folder 25)
    - George Peabody College—Miscellaneous, Feb. 18, 1944—Aug. 18, 1946 (Folder 26)
    - George Peabody College—Bulletin—Division of Music, 1944-1945; 1945-1947; Music at Peabody Oct. (Folder 27)
    - George Peabody College—Bulletin—Division of Music, 1947-1949; 1949-1951 (Folder 28)
    - Fisk University—Festival of Music and Fine Arts, Sara Holroyd, trumpet, April 19-22, 1944 (Folder 29)
    - Peabody Demonstration School, May 5, 1944--May 24, 1946 (Folder 30)
    - Ryman Auditorium—V.E. Day First Anniversary, May 8, 1946 (Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Peabody Reflector, June 1945—Alumni and Student News (Folder 32)
    - Peabody Reflector—Miscellaneous Articles (Folder 33)
    - Peabody Reflector—Miscellaneous Articles (Folder 34)
    - Peabody Reflector—Miscellaneous Articles (Folder 35)
  - Photographs
    - Sara Holroyd “Miss Peabody” and with other Peabody musicians (Folder 36)